FATIH ARI

Aspiring Developer / Mechanical Engineer | Powercoders Participant Aarhaldenstrasse 6, 3052 Zollikofen | 25.06.1982 | Residence permit B fatih.ari@powercoders.org | +41 77 999 43 97

GitHub | Learning Blog | LinkedIn

Languages: English (C1), German (B2), Turkish (mother tongue)

IT Skills: Intermediate: Java, JavaScript, Git, GitHub, Agile (Scrum)

Elementary: HTML, CSS, SQL, Spring Framework 5

Beginner: Testing(Java), React



SUMMARY

I am an experienced Mechanical Engineer with 11 years of engineering and project managing experience in different sectors. I have also been self-learning web engineering disciplines for a year as an alternative profession. I have a passion for learning IT technologies to go further in this way.

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2017 – 08/2018 Manager of the Production Unit, HYT Group, Ankara, Turkey

- Outlined work plans, wrote timelines and determined resources

- Assigned the employees and controlled their tasks

- Tracked production output, quality and efficiency

09/2016 – 01/2017 Mechanical Engineer, HYT Group, Ankara, Turkey

- Designed ventilation units via 3D design tools

- Worked on bending and cutting machines

- Prepared catalogs and manuals

02/2012– 07/2016 Project Manager/ Deputy Director, Banknote Printing Plant of Turkey, Ankara,

Turkey

- Achieved to cut down the expenses approximately 18 Million TL

- Managed to complete five different projects from concept design to production

- Optimized production flow by rearranging the manufacturing shift plan

12/2006 – 02/2012 Mechanical Engineer, Banknote Printing Plant of Turkey, Ankara, Turkey

- Achieved 9% reduction in downtime due to the failure

EDUCATION

09/2020 – 12/2020 Powercoders – Coding Academy for Refugees, Zurich, Switzerland

- Foundations in HTML, CSS, JavaScript; specialization tracks upcoming

- Weekly business & social skills training (teamwork, communication, etc.)

01/2019 – 12/2019	 IT Club Oberland – Zürich, Switzerland Web programming basics Programming with Java and Spring framework 	
01/2020 – 07/2020	Guest Student, Bern Fachhochschule / Industrial Engineering and Management, Biel/Bienne, Switzerland - Completed a course in supply chain and logistics management - Learnt basics of Industry 4.0 - Created a concept design of a product to produce in CP Factory - Prepared a conceptual adaptation of Industry 4.0 Lab	
09/2014 – 2018	Master of Business Administration (Incomplete) , Gazi University, Ankara, Turkey - Uncompleted Thesis: "Awareness of the Banknotes: The objective and subjective knowledge of Users on Discriminating Fake Banknotes"	
09/2005 – 08/2008	 M.Sc. in Mechanical Engineering, Marmara University, Istanbul, Turkey Master Thesis: "Design And Production Of A Welding Robot " İstanbul-2008 / Supervisor: Prof. Dr.Bülent EKİCİ 	
09/2000 – 06/2005	B.Sc. in Mechanical Engineering, Marmara University, Istanbul, Turkey	
EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES		

02/2020 – Present	Volunteer, Zollikofe-Mitenang, Zollikofen	
-------------------	---	--

- Supporting the residents of Zollikofen in the old people's center or at home with various activities in everyday life.

CERTIFICATION

	•
09/2020	HTML, CSS and Javascript for Web Developers, John Hopkins University,
	Coursera
08/2020	HTML Essential Training, Linkedin Learning.
07/2020	B2 German Telc Certificate
04/2020	Java Programming "Arrays, Lists, and Structured Data", Duke University,
	Coursera
01/2020	Agile with Atlassian Jira, Atlassian, Coursera
01/2020	Java Programming "Solving Problems with Software", Duke University, Coursera
01/2020	Visual Elements of User Interface Design, California Institute of the Arts, Coursera

HOBBIES

Travelling, cycling, and table tennis

REFERENCES

- Hussam Allaham, Powercoders Industry Lead, hussam.allaham@powercoders.org,
 +41 77 906 16 27
- Ebubekir Kaya, General Manager, International Language School, <u>info@ils-bern.ch</u>, +41 31 556 35 89
- Louis Amport, German Tandem Support, Hiphop Center Bern, l.amport@hiphopcenter.ch, +41 31 511 21 14 (Mon. 14:00-19:00 / Wed. 13:00-16:00)